<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>product on Santosh Desiraju</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/tags/product/</link><description>Recent content in product on Santosh Desiraju</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 18:00:53 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/tags/product/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Solving few issues to get up and running with Oracle VM</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/how-to-oracle-vm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/how-to-oracle-vm/</guid><description>A Quick Guide to cover the following:
Enable full screen/Screen Resolution Virtualization not enabled Enable full screen/Screen Resolution:
Have you ever struggled with a virtual machine that just won&amp;rsquo;t fit your screen? I certainly have, and let me tell you, it is frustrating. After countless Google searches which leads to stackoverflow and even asking AI for help which sources probably from the same stackoverflow pages, I finally cracked the code. Here&amp;rsquo;s my simple solution for resizing VMs to match your screen resolution:</description></item><item><title>My favorite product coming out of the pandemic</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/fourth_post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/fourth_post/</guid><description>I got introduced to several products during what I call &amp;rsquo;the zoom pandemic.&amp;rsquo; Quite a lot of them were related to dogs. All thanks to Mocha - our 7 month old aussie (as of this writing). One product which turned out to be a showstopper for me was Masterclass. I love how Masterclass makes it easy for me to access knowledge directly from top experts in various fields. It feels like on-demand tutoring from all-star tutors!</description></item><item><title>Robinhood, your website is broken and it needs your attention now</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/third_post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/third_post/</guid><description>Hitting into live bugs ignites my left brain at that very moment. Soon a series of rabbit hole explorations ensue, root causing it while I go about my original task. When I ruminate on it a bit later I come up with proposals to resolve and make things better. Giving my right brain its share of work. Here&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ve bumped into:
Robinhood&amp;rsquo;s mobile app has unlocked a power user group — millennials.</description></item></channel></rss>