<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>travel on Santosh Desiraju</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/tags/travel/</link><description>Recent content in travel on Santosh Desiraju</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 18:00:53 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Japan 2024</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/japan-trip-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/japan-trip-2024/</guid><description>Travel Highlights of Japan After years of dreaming about it, We finally embarked on our journey to Japan in 2024. Here are some of the unforgettable experiences that made this trip truly remarkable:
Effortless Travel with the Suica Pass: The Suica pass simplifies intra-city travel, allowing for seamless navigation through urban areas. However, be mindful that it may occasionally present challenges with inter-city travel. Embrace the Local Culture: Tourism in Japan is at an all-time high.</description></item><item><title>Mexico 2022</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/cabo-trip-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/cabo-trip-2022/</guid><description>Travel highlights of Cabo! Cabo San Lucas offers the perfect blend of stunning landscapes and vibrant culture, making it a must-visit destination. Here are my travel highlights from this beautiful locale:
Car Rental is Essential: To fully explore Cabo, renting a car is highly recommended. The hotels and resorts are often spread out, and having your own transportation makes it easy to access various attractions and beaches. Resort Vibes: Many resorts in Cabo feel like an extension of the United States, offering familiar amenities and services while still allowing you to enjoy the unique charm of Mexico.</description></item></channel></rss>