<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on Santosh Desiraju</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/tags/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on Santosh Desiraju</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 18:00:53 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Weekend Project: Reviving 2009 iMac - From El Capitan to Linux Mint</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/imac-restore/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/imac-restore/</guid><description>A Weekend Project: Reviving My 2009 iMac - From El Capitan to Linux Mint This weekend turned into an unexpected tech adventure when I decided to breathe new life into my old iMac (2.66 GHz Intel Core 2 Duo, 8GB RAM, NVIDIA GeForce 9400 256MB). What started as a simple browser upgrade spiraled into a full system overhaul - and I learned quite a bit along the way. The macOS Struggle It all began with trying to get a modern browser running on OS X El Capitan.</description></item><item><title>Git push using token</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/how-to-git-authentication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/how-to-git-authentication/</guid><description>Resolving GitHub Authentication Issues: Using Personal Access Tokens Have you encountered this message when attempting to git push?
remote: Support for password authentication was removed on August 13, 2021. remote: Please see https://docs.github.com/get-started/getting-started-with-git/about-remote-repositories#cloning-with-https-urls for information on currently recommended modes of authentication. fatal: Authentication failed for &amp;lsquo;https://github.com/desirajusantosh/&amp;lt;&amp;gt;&amp;rsquo; text
Don&amp;rsquo;t worry! GitHub has transitioned to more secure authentication methods. Here&amp;rsquo;s how to resolve this issue using a Personal Access Token (PAT):
Creating a Personal Access Token Go to your GitHub account settings Navigate to &amp;ldquo;Developer settings&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Personal access tokens&amp;rdquo; Click &amp;ldquo;Generate new token&amp;rdquo; Set a descriptive name for your token Choose an expiration date (or select &amp;ldquo;No expiration&amp;rdquo; if needed) Select necessary scopes: For most operations, the &amp;lsquo;repo&amp;rsquo; scope is sufficient This grants full control of private repositories Click &amp;ldquo;Generate token&amp;rdquo; and copy it immediately Using Your Personal Access Token Once you have your PAT, you can use it in place of your password for Git operations:</description></item><item><title>Setting up a python environment using miniforge</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/setting-up-miniforge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/setting-up-miniforge/</guid><description>Why Use Miniforge? The default Python version installed on most systems is often outdated and not recommended for development. Miniforge provides a minimal installer for Conda, allowing you to create isolated Python environments with the latest versions and necessary packages.
Step-by-Step Guide 1. Check Your Current Python Installation First, let&amp;rsquo;s check if you have Python installed and where it&amp;rsquo;s located:
which python
This should return either empty or point to /usr/bin/python.</description></item><item><title>Japan 2024</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/japan-trip-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/japan-trip-2024/</guid><description>Travel Highlights of Japan After years of dreaming about it, We finally embarked on our journey to Japan in 2024. Here are some of the unforgettable experiences that made this trip truly remarkable:
Effortless Travel with the Suica Pass: The Suica pass simplifies intra-city travel, allowing for seamless navigation through urban areas. However, be mindful that it may occasionally present challenges with inter-city travel. Embrace the Local Culture: Tourism in Japan is at an all-time high.</description></item><item><title>Mexico 2022</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/cabo-trip-2022/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/cabo-trip-2022/</guid><description>Travel highlights of Cabo! Cabo San Lucas offers the perfect blend of stunning landscapes and vibrant culture, making it a must-visit destination. Here are my travel highlights from this beautiful locale:
Car Rental is Essential: To fully explore Cabo, renting a car is highly recommended. The hotels and resorts are often spread out, and having your own transportation makes it easy to access various attractions and beaches. Resort Vibes: Many resorts in Cabo feel like an extension of the United States, offering familiar amenities and services while still allowing you to enjoy the unique charm of Mexico.</description></item><item><title>How to - Pandas</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/how-to-pandas/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/how-to-pandas/</guid><description>import pandas as pd # Displaying complete dataframe pd.set_option(&amp;#34;display.max_rows&amp;#34;, None, &amp;#34;display.max_columns&amp;#34;, None) #pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.max_colwidth&amp;#39;, None) pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.max_colwidth&amp;#39;, 199) pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.height&amp;#39;,1000) pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.max_rows&amp;#39;,500) pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.max_columns&amp;#39;,500) pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.width&amp;#39;,1000) pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.max_columns&amp;#39;, None) # or 1000 pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.max_rows&amp;#39;, None) # or 1000 #pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.max_colwidth&amp;#39;, None) # or 199 pd.set_option(&amp;#39;display.max_colwidth&amp;#39;, -1) fh = &amp;#34;/path/to/file.csv&amp;#34; ## Reading csv file df = pd.read_csv(fh) df = pd.read_csv(fh,header=None) df = pd.read_csv(fh,header=None,sep=&amp;#39;\s+&amp;#39;,engine=python,index_col=False) df = pd.read_csv(fh,header=None,sep=&amp;#39;\s+&amp;#39;,engine=python,index_col=False, names=[&amp;#39;name&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;id&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;start&amp;#39;,&amp;#39;end&amp;#39;]) ## Working with index df.set_index(&amp;#39;name&amp;#39;,inplace=True) df.set_index(&amp;#39;name&amp;#39;,drop=False) df.reset_index() df.reset_index(drop=True) # Searching becomes easy with indexing df.</description></item><item><title>How to - Working with excel and python</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/how-to-working-with-excel-and-python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/how-to-working-with-excel-and-python/</guid><description>References: https://automatetheboringstuff.com/2e/chapter13/
https://openpyxl.readthedocs.io/en/stable/worksheet_tables.html
https://www.geeksforgeeks.org/how-to-automate-an-excel-sheet-in-python/
https://python-forum.io/thread-32833.html</description></item><item><title>Solving few issues to get up and running with Oracle VM</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/how-to-oracle-vm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/how-to-oracle-vm/</guid><description>A Quick Guide to cover the following:
Enable full screen/Screen Resolution Virtualization not enabled Enable full screen/Screen Resolution:
Have you ever struggled with a virtual machine that just won&amp;rsquo;t fit your screen? I certainly have, and let me tell you, it is frustrating. After countless Google searches which leads to stackoverflow and even asking AI for help which sources probably from the same stackoverflow pages, I finally cracked the code.</description></item><item><title>My favorite product coming out of the pandemic</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/fourth_post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jun 2021 18:00:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/fourth_post/</guid><description>I got introduced to several products during what I call &amp;lsquo;the zoom pandemic.&amp;rsquo; Quite a lot of them were related to dogs. All thanks to Mocha - our 7 month old aussie (as of this writing). One product which turned out to be a showstopper for me was Masterclass. I love how Masterclass makes it easy for me to access knowledge directly from top experts in various fields. It feels like on-demand tutoring from all-star tutors!</description></item><item><title>Robinhood, your website is broken and it needs your attention now</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/third_post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/third_post/</guid><description>Hitting into live bugs ignites my left brain at that very moment. Soon a series of rabbit hole explorations ensue, root causing it while I go about my original task. When I ruminate on it a bit later I come up with proposals to resolve and make things better. Giving my right brain its share of work. Here&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ve bumped into:
Robinhood&amp;rsquo;s mobile app has unlocked a power user group — millennials.</description></item><item><title>Run up to running</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/second_post/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/second_post/</guid><description>Consistency is key. 💪
When the activity is not yet a habit, progress straddles on consistency. I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading and listening on running quite a bit the past few months. With inspiration still fresh in my head and also to keep myself active during the WFH situation, started running. During the evenings of August, around 7PM, my routine was a run around my block. It was pretty hot this summer in Bay area.</description></item><item><title>Markdown Mastery: A Procrastinator's Guide to Formatting</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/how-to-markdown/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/how-to-markdown/</guid><description>Ever find yourself staring at a blank text file, trying to remember how to make text bold or create a heading? You&amp;rsquo;re not alone! As a sporadic blogger, I&amp;rsquo;ve been there. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the world of Markdown - the secret weapon for forgetful writers like us.
I kept forgetting how to format my posts every time I decided to grace the internet with my thoughts. Instead of relying on my unreliable memory, I decided to create this cheat sheet.</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/first_post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 20:18:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://desirajusantosh.github.io/santosh-blog/blog/first_post/</guid><description>Hello World, after several attempts. Here I&amp;rsquo;m with my space on the internet.</description></item></channel></rss>